I completely fell in love with 3D. I think 3D is an amazing tool. Of course, it's more easy and understandable to understand a 3D drawing than a 2D sketch flat.
It gives me a great visual for when I need to sell something or when I communicate to other BU's. It really shows the product what it will look like in store.
The great thing about using 3D is that there is no miscommunication between the parties because the 3D drawing is actually a really accurate representation of the final outcome.
It's amazing the 3D of modeling, texturing and styling. It's very close to the reality.
It's a way of collaborating more with other departments. From hand sketching, going right into pattern and into 3D helps a lot in making everybody understand.
Yes, I think it's great to start designing in a 3D surface. That way you can start looking into all the different angles in order to craft your ideas to real life proportions.
We also updated some patterns in 3D because we could visualize what would be the best solution.
We also prepared some presentations where we used 3D to explain our marketing colleagues some pattern issues or some pattern problems.
3D modelling softwares are helping our design process to create a more conscious and realistic design.
The 3D for me is definitely about the visualisation and the quicker that we can get marketing to understand the sketches
and then all the work done up front straight into development. It's really time-saving.
It's a good understanding between the designer and me and I think it's also a positive aspect
when we are talking to the LO and the factory guys.
The process, the design process is automatically changing.
You can make decisions much quicker, you work closely together.